

Phil Griswold

- **T** 615-495-3912
- **E** philgriswold@me.com
- A 2805 Shadow Lane Nashville, TN 37216

About Me

Early in my work life I channeled all of my curiosity and desire to create into my first love music. I followed that desire down some adventurous roads and over many peaks and valleys. At some point along the way, having already experienced many of the ups and downs of the artist life, I found myself still wanting to create but in a new medium - one that might chart a meaningful yet more stable journey. Software development came to me at the right time as the most fitting answer. While I find it to be challenging at times, I am fascinated by the art, the scope, and the real life application of it. I have also found that It is a world big and wide enough to find one's own space in and the most logical new place for me to park my curiosity.

Education

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Development - August 2019 - present

BERKLEE COLLEGE OF MUSIC

Bachelor of Art in Music 2006

Professional Experience

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Six-month full-stack bootcamp

- -Built web applications utilizing the building block languages for full stack development such as Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, and C#.
- Learned how to navigate the intricacies of the software development platform GitHub while creating projects in class.
- Worked with a team on a project called "Welcome to Nashville" that involved learning how to fetch data from API's and creating modular Javascript files.
- -- Worked on team project called "Nutshell" that involved creating a social media platform allowing users to login/register, add friends, edit/delete tasks and events, and participate in a chat room.
- Created an individual capstone project using React, Reactstrap, and Bootstrap called "The Ramenator" that allows users to find and review the best Ramen shops in Tokyo..

Additional Work Experience

WIT COURIER

July 2016 - August 2019

-Worked for a small medical courier company that handled and delivered all of the most vital information and sensitive items such as medication, blood work, and lab charts for Tennessee Oncology.

MUSIC TEACHER FOR JOELTON MIDDLE SCHOOL

August 2015 - May 2016

- Taught 7th and 8th graders with creative and engaging lesson plans that involved learning how to read music, exposure to various world music styles, and creative collaboration in small teams..

FREELANCE MUSICIAN

January 2002 - May 2016

- Toured and performed as a drummer for various musical artists. Some credits, starting from most recent, include The Farewell Drifters, Ariel Bui, Riley Green, Leith Loftin, Kris Roche, Esperanza Spalding, and Elizabeth and the Catapult.